<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cost on Wilhelm Codes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cost on Wilhelm Codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 21:13:29 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Save Money By Keeping Your AWS Account Clean</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/save-money-by-keeping-your-aws-account-clean/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/save-money-by-keeping-your-aws-account-clean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At my current role, we manage just under 20 AWS accounts. Their uses vary from production workloads, to dedicated CI/CD environments, sandboxed areas for our engineers to experiment in, log aggregation, the list goes on. Needless to say, we like to isolate our concerns across our AWS org.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because we have so many to manage and not a whole lot of people power ( it’s just 2 of us ), it gets easy for a lot of hidden costs to pop up here and there if we aren’t vigilant enough with housekeeping.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deleting Massive S3 Buckets the Easy Way.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/deleting-massive-s3-buckets-the-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/deleting-massive-s3-buckets-the-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ok-&#34;&gt;Ok&amp;hellip; 🥱&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right, so, I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of decommissioning a service at the moment and I have to do the typical process of performing final snapshots and cleaning up extant resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this particular service, we have an  &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extract,_transform,_load&#34;&gt;ETL&lt;/a&gt;  process that stores raw data points for downstream ingestion by some other&amp;hellip; thing. Anyway, the storage mechanism for this is a cross-region replicated S3 bucket containing just over 10 &lt;em&gt;million&lt;/em&gt; objects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
